<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.9.6" xml:lang="en-US">
  <compounddef id="indexpage" kind="page">
    <compoundname>index</compoundname>
    <title>EMath++ Project</title>
    <briefdescription>
    </briefdescription>
    <detaileddescription>
<sect1 id="index_1intro">
<title>Introduction</title>
<para>This is a project that aims to provide some wrapper classes for algebraic mathematical concepts.<linebreak/>
It includes the Monomial and Polynomial classes for general calculus, plus a Parser for transforming std::string to Polynomial objects.<linebreak/>
It also comes with a Termial interface for doing multiple operatios with polynomials: arithemtic, root finding, graphical representation.<linebreak/>
 The library is currently in expansion. It will include in the future support for Exponential, Trigonometric and Radical functions.<linebreak/>
Any feedback is much appreciated!</para>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="index_1libinstall">
<title>Library Installation</title>
<para>The project comes with a folder with some bash files that complete some Meson related tasks.<linebreak/>
All bash files must be executed from the project&apos;s root directory to work properly.<linebreak/>
To install the project, there is only need to execute two of them files.<linebreak/>
Once installed just include the <ref refid="emath_8h" kindref="compound">emath.h</ref> or <ref refid="eparser_8h" kindref="compound">eparser.h</ref> header files in your code respectively and link them with their implementation.</para>
<sect2 id="index_1step1">
<title>Step one: Setup the Project</title>
<para>To setup the Meson project run the setup.sh bash file: <programlisting><codeline><highlight class="normal">bash<sp/>./scripts/setup.sh</highlight></codeline>
</programlisting></para>
</sect2>
<sect2 id="index_1step2">
<title>Step two: Install the Library</title>
<para>To install the emath library run the install.sh bash file:</para>
<para><programlisting><codeline><highlight class="normal">bash<sp/>./scripts/install.sh</highlight></codeline>
</programlisting></para>
<para><simplesect kind="note"><para>You will need a privileged user&apos;s credentials</para>
</simplesect>
</para>
</sect2>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="index_1test">
<title>Testing</title>
<para>The project comes with some test files located in the test folder.<linebreak/>
To test that the library code works properly run the following bash file: <programlisting><codeline><highlight class="normal">bash<sp/>./scripts/test.sh</highlight></codeline>
</programlisting></para>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="index_1terinstall">
<title>Interface Installation</title>
<para>The project comes with a folder with some bash files that complete some Meson related tasks.<linebreak/>
All bash files must be executed from the project&apos;s root directory to work properly.<linebreak/>
There are two ways to install the Interface, when following the Library Installation instructions or manually as explained here:</para>
<sect2 id="index_1istep1">
<title>Step one: Setup the Project</title>
<para>To setup the Meson project run the setup.sh bash file: <programlisting><codeline><highlight class="normal">bash<sp/>./scripts/setup.sh</highlight></codeline>
</programlisting></para>
</sect2>
<sect2 id="index_1istep2">
<title>Step two: Compile the Interface</title>
<para>To compile the Interface run the compile.sh bash file: <programlisting><codeline><highlight class="normal">bash<sp/>./scripts/compile.sh</highlight></codeline>
</programlisting></para>
</sect2>
<sect2 id="index_1istep3">
<title>Step three: Move to final directory</title>
<para>To finish installing the Interface choose one of the two executable files: emath_cli_d or emath_cli_s. The executable ending in _d is the dynamic version and the one ending in _s is the static version.</para>
<para><simplesect kind="note"><para>When installing to a Windows machine the executable files will have prefixed &apos;.exe&apos; </para>
</simplesect>
<simplesect kind="note"><para>If the dynamic version does not work try the static version: This could resolve missing dependencies</para>
</simplesect>
</para>
</sect2>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="index_1terusage">
<title>Interface Usage</title>
<sect2 id="index_1launching">
<title>Launching the Interface</title>
<para>To launch the Interface just open a console and cd to the directory with the binaries: <programlisting><codeline><highlight class="normal">cd<sp/>/path/to/emath_cli_dir</highlight></codeline>
<codeline><highlight class="normal">./emath_cli_d</highlight></codeline>
</programlisting></para>
<para>Or if they are in the PATH environment variable call them normally: <programlisting><codeline><highlight class="normal">emath_cli_d</highlight></codeline>
</programlisting></para>
<para><simplesect kind="note"><para>We will use emath_cli_d as the binary executable, but if you installed the static version you should call emath_cli_s instead</para>
</simplesect>
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2 id="index_1adding">
<title>Adding polynomials</title>
<para>To add polynomials to the cache and consecuently be able to operate with them you should press &apos;e&apos; on the main menu. Then you should write the polynomial in the following markup [ 3/2x^2 + 2*2.2x - 5 ] and press enter.</para>
<para><simplesect kind="note"><para>If you have added toomany polynomials to the cache a scroll function will be enabled, cycle pressing tab on the main or operation menus until the polynomials window is focused and the press the arrow functions to scroll.</para>
</simplesect>
<image type="html" name="screenshot_one.png"></image>
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2 id="index_1removing">
<title>Removing polynomials</title>
<para>To remove polynomials from the cache and consecuently delete them you should press &apos;q&apos; on the main menu. Then you should write the number corresponding to the polynomial&apos;s index.</para>
</sect2>
<sect2 id="index_1operation">
<title>New operation</title>
<para>Once at least one polynomial has been added you can press space on the main menu to enter to the operation menu:</para>
<para><image type="html" name="screenshot_three.png"></image>
</para>
<para>Now you have a variety of choices: numbered different operations and arithmetic operations.</para>
</sect2>
<sect2 id="index_1arithmetic">
<title>Arithmetic operation</title>
<para>Once in the operation menu, you can press space again to input a arithmetic operation. Arithmetic operations consist of +, -, *, / operations beetwen the polynomial indexes. Here is an example of what you would input to multiply the polynomial with index 0 to the one with index 1 and add to that what results the polynomial with index 2: [ 0 * 1 + 2 ]. Then the results will be printed, and you will ahve to press any key to continue.</para>
<para><simplesect kind="note"><para>Higher grade operations like multiplication and division are computer before their lower grade counter parts addition and substraction </para>
</simplesect>
<simplesect kind="note"><para>If you want to save the resulting polynomial to cache write the &apos;_&apos; character as the first character and then write the rest of the operation normally</para>
</simplesect>
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2 id="index_1evaluate">
<title>Evaluate operation</title>
<para>To get the value of y for some x, you make a evaluate operation. Press 1 on the operation menu, input the polynomial&apos;s index and then input the x&apos;s value.</para>
</sect2>
<sect2 id="index_1derint">
<title>Derivative and Integral operation</title>
<para>Both these operations are done in an indentical way: Press 2 or 3 respectively on the operation menu and then input the polynomial&apos;s index.</para>
</sect2>
<sect2 id="index_1root">
<title>Root finding operation</title>
<para>To find the real and complex roots of a polynomial when on the operation menu: Press 4 and then input the polynomial&apos;s index. The roots will be printed inside parenthesis.</para>
<para><image type="html" name="screenshot_four.png"></image>
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2 id="index_1draw">
<title>Drawing operation</title>
<para>To draw a polynomial in the Cartesian plane: Press 5 on the operation menu and then input the polynomial&apos;s index. A new window will open showing the polynomail on the Cartesian plane. You then can move with the arrow keys around the Cartesian plane and resize the window to expand the Cartesian plane.</para>
<para><image type="html" name="screenshot_two.png"></image>
 </para>
</sect2>
</sect1>
    </detaileddescription>
    <location file="include/emath.h"/>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
